<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Chronicles of a Ruby Rube]]></title>
  <link href="http://kimberlymurphy.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kimberlymurphy.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-05T15:13:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://kimberlymurphy.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kimberly Murphy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just A Sip: Day 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://kimberlymurphy.github.io/blog/2014/02/04/just-a-sip-day-1/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-04T12:21:10-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://kimberlymurphy.github.io/blog/2014/02/04/just-a-sip-day-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="left" src="http://www.scotduke.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/03/drink-out-of-a-hose.jpg" width="425" height="282" title="image" alt="images"></p>

<p>I like to learn, I really do.  I seek out situations which provide that opportunity.  That said, I’m not sure that my approach to learning is currently the most healthy/functional.  As I get older&mdash;rather than wiser&mdash;I feel more self-conscious, introverted and unsure.</p>

<p>Which certainly influences my approach.  One minute I&rsquo;m agitated because if I asked every question that came into my head or branched for the detour such musings would launch, I’d not only disrupt things for others, I’d have a hard time making it through a simple task with any sense of continuity.  That said, my response to this often means telling myself to chill-out&hellip;then finding a gear where I sit back and let the information flow my way like a 10-month-old being fed smashed peas: some content makes it in, a fair amount misses.</p>

<h2>Go, find balance.</h2>


<p>I try to put things in the context of drinking from that firehose, and realize the means some of it will necessarily be missed, but that also worries me.  The reality is I’ve had experiences where things eased and I’d later wonder how I ever felt so daunted, but I’ve also had ones where (while I didn’t quit on Mr. Miyagi) there wasn&rsquo;t enough connection for me to reach all the ahh-ha moments.</p>

<p>Somebody once told me a story of the best student they ever knew: this kid who unabashedly asked questions.  Questions about everything/anything.  Which theoretically meant everyone learned more.  Though I’ve been in classes where someone does this and seen the side of it as also potentially detrimental to others in what it limits being covered.</p>

<p>I guess striving for balance in approach is the best I can do.  A balance where I don’t ignore what confuses me, but I don’t necessarily address every (often irrelevant or later addressed) concern/tangent that pops into my head.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
